Bill Pelke Papers
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- General Activism, 1984-2000, Undated; nam_apap205-6; 5.08 cubic feet
  - Resist, 1995; nam_apap205-6_422 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Resist, 1996; nam_apap205-6_423 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Resist, 1996; nam_apap205-6_424 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Resist, 1997; nam_apap205-6_425 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Resist, 1997; nam_apap205-6_426 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Resist, 1997; nam_apap205-6_427 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Resist, 1998; nam_apap205-6_428 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Resist, 1998; nam_apap205-6_429 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Resist, 1998; nam_apap205-6_430 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Resist, 1998; nam_apap205-6_431 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Resist, 1999; nam_apap205-6_432 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Rethinking Prisons, 1992-1993; nam_apap205-6_433 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Revolutionary Communist Party, U.S.A.Revolutionary Worker, 1997; nam_apap205-6_434 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - The Rising Sun, 1993; nam_apap205-6_435 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Robert West Defense Fund, Undated; nam_apap205-6_436 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Rock and Rap Confidential, 1993; nam_apap205-6_437 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Rural Southern Voice for Peace -Voices, 1995; nam_apap205-6_438 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Safer Society Press - Catalog, 1999; nam_apap205-6_439 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Save Our Sons and Daughters, 1990; 1997; nam_apap205-6_440 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Seamless Garment Network, 1993-1999; nam_apap205-6_441 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - SOLPAE, 1995-1996; Undated; nam_apap205-6_442 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - SOLPAE -In Solidarity, 1993; nam_apap205-6_443 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - SOLPAE -In Solidarity, 1994; nam_apap205-6_444 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - SOLPAE -In Solidarity, 1995; nam_apap205-6_445 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - SOLPAE -In Solidarity, 1996; nam_apap205-6_446 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Southern Center for Human Rights -Human Rights Report, 1999; nam_apap205-6_447 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 1989; 1992; Undated; nam_apap205-6_448 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Southern Poverty Law Center, Undated; nam_apap205-6_449 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Stop the Executions of People, Inc., 1992; Undated; nam_apap205-6_450 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Symposium: Are Executions in New York Inevitable?, 1995; nam_apap205-6_451 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Tennessee Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers, 1994; nam_apap205-6_452 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Tennessee Coalition to Abolish State Killing (TCASK), 1997; Undated; nam_apap205-6_453 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Texans Against State Killing, 1991; 1993; Undated; nam_apap205-6_454 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Texas Abolition Network, 1993; Undated; nam_apap205-6_455 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Texas Abolition Network -The Network News, 1992; nam_apap205-6_456 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Texas Abolition Network -The Network News, 1993; nam_apap205-6_457 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Texas Alliance for Human Needs, 1996-1998; Undated; nam_apap205-6_458 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Texas Alliance for Human Needs - Newsletters, 1993; nam_apap205-6_459 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Texas Alliance for Human Needs - Newsletters, 1994; nam_apap205-6_460 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Texas Alliance for Human Needs - Newsletters, 1995; nam_apap205-6_461 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Texas Alliance for Human Needs - Newsletters, 1996; nam_apap205-6_462 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Texas Alliance for Human Needs - Newsletters, 1997; nam_apap205-6_463 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Texas Alliance for Human Needs - Newsletters, 1998; nam_apap205-6_464 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Texas Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, Undated; nam_apap205-6_465 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - The Texas Observer, 1997-1998; nam_apap205-6_466 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Transnational, 1994; 1996; nam_apap205-6_467 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Tree of Life Campaign, 1995-1996; nam_apap205-6_468 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Unitarian Universalists Against the Death Penalty -Witness for Life, 1998; nam_apap205-6_469 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - United Farm Workers -Food Justice, 1994; nam_apap205-6_470 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - United Farm Workers -Food Justice, 1995; nam_apap205-6_471 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - United Steelworkers of America -The Organizer, 1991; nam_apap205-6_472 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - United Steelworkers of America -The Organizer, 1995; nam_apap205-6_473 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - United Steelworkers of America -The Organizer, 1998; nam_apap205-6_474 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Unity Day - Button, 1994; nam_apap205-6_475 (Oversize 5, Item 16)
  - Unity Day Project, 1993-1994; Undated; nam_apap205-6_476 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Victim Offender Reconciliation Program, 1993; Undated; nam_apap205-6_477 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Victim Offender Services -Gatherings, 1995; nam_apap205-6_478 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Virginia Coalition on Jails and Prisons, 1988; 1990-1993; nam_apap205-6_479 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Virginia Coalition on Jails and Prisons - 1992 Program Report, circa 1993; nam_apap205-6_480 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Virginians for Alternatives to State Killing, 1993-1994; Undated; nam_apap205-6_481 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty (VADP), 1996-1997; Undated; nam_apap205-6_482 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty -VADP Action, 1995; nam_apap205-6_483 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty -VADP Action, 1996; nam_apap205-6_484 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty -VADP Action, 1997; nam_apap205-6_485 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty -VADP Action, 1998; nam_apap205-6_486 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Voices for the Condemned Newsletter, 1995; Undated; nam_apap205-6_487 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Voices from the Inside - Church of the Covenant: Unconditional Pardon, 1992; nam_apap205-6_488 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - War Resisters League, 1990; 1995-1996; nam_apap205-6_489 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Washington Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers, 1994; nam_apap205-6_490 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Western Missouri Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1997-1999; Undated; nam_apap205-6_491 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Wisconsin CURE, 1994; Undated; nam_apap205-6_492 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Why do we kill people - Button, Undated; nam_apap205-6_493 (Oversize 5, Item 15)
  - Workers Vanguard, 1988; nam_apap205-6_494 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Workers Vanguard, 1989; nam_apap205-6_495 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Workers Vanguard, 1994; nam_apap205-6_496 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Workers World, 1988; nam_apap205-6_497 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - World Congress on Forgiveness - Jerusalem 2000, 1997; Undated; nam_apap205-6_498 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Subject Files, 1965-1999, Undated; nam_apap205-7; 2.25 cubic feet
  This series contains biographical material related to Bill Pelke, reference material on the capital punishment, photographs, draft and non-published articles, religious materials, and poetry, songs, plays, and other artistic materials created by death row inmates or about the death penalty collected by Bill Pelke.
  - Abolition Day speech, 1993; nam_apap205-7_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address Given by Marie Deans, 1986; nam_apap205-7_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Janey Appleseed - Draft Article, Undated; nam_apap205-7_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Article from Death Row, Undated; nam_apap205-7_4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Artistic Works, 1983; 1991; 1993; 1995; Undated; nam_apap205-7_5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - " Better Off Dead " - T.V. movie, 1992; nam_apap205-7_6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Biddle Publishing - Frontiers of Justice, 1997; nam_apap205-7_7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ariel Brugger, 1996; nam_apap205-7_8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - E.L. Brugan - Turner- articles, 1990; 1994; nam_apap205-7_9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Robin Casarjian - draft articles, Undated; nam_apap205-7_10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Child's Drawings, Undated; nam_apap205-7_11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ashanti Chimurenga - First Draft Proposal, 1992; nam_apap205-7_12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Paula Cooper - Disciplinary Hearing, 1995; nam_apap205-7_13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Death Penalty Petition, Undated; nam_apap205-7_14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Grim Reaper Decoration, Undated; nam_apap205-7_15 (Oversized 6, Item 1)
  - House Bill 1802, 1991; nam_apap205-7_16 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Humor, 1994; Undated; nam_apap205-7_17 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mary Hutchinson - Declaration of Life, 1995; nam_apap205-7_18 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - In Your Hands - Community Action Guide for Human Rights Year and Beyond, 1998; nam_apap205-7_19 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - International Court of Justice, 1998; nam_apap205-7_20 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Earnest James Jr. - " Where do I Sign ", Undated; nam_apap205-7_21 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Charlie King - concert, 1995; nam_apap205-7_22 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Morris Family News, 1996; nam_apap205-7_23 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Not in My Name" - Rubber Stamp, Undated; nam_apap205-7_24 (Oversize 5, Item 6)
  - Bill Pelke Articles, 1992; 1994-1995; Undated; nam_apap205-7_25 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bill Pelke - Biographical Materials, 1965; 1977; 1993-1994; Undated; nam_apap205-7_26 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bill Pelke - Calendar, 1995; nam_apap205-7_27 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bill Pelke - Calendars, May-December, 1994; nam_apap205-7_28 (Flat-file 1)
  - Bill Pelke - Calendars, 1995; nam_apap205-7_29 (Flat-file 2)
  - Bill Pelke - Calendars, August-September, 1997; nam_apap205-7_30 (Flat-file 3)
  - Bill Pelke - grandmother, 1985; Undated; nam_apap205-7_31 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bill Pelke - Italy trip, 1988; nam_apap205-7_32 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bill Pelke - name tags, Undated; nam_apap205-7_33 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bill Pelke - notes, Undated; nam_apap205-7_34 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bill Pelke - notes, Undated; nam_apap205-7_35 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bill Pelke - notes, Undated; nam_apap205-7_36 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bill Pelke - Washington D.C., Demonstration Arrest and Trial, 1997; nam_apap205-7_37 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bill Pelker - web searchers, 1996-1998; nam_apap205-7_38 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Pending Execution of William Andrews, 1992; nam_apap205-7_39 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Phillipine Focus, 1995-1999; nam_apap205-7_40 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Photographs, Undated; nam_apap205-7_41 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Michael John Poirier, 1993-1997; nam_apap205-7_42 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Punching Nun Puppet, Undated; nam_apap205-7_43 (Oversized 4, Item 1)
  - Lisa Radelet - Report on Consensual Executions, 1990; nam_apap205-7_44 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Reference Material, 1990-1998; Undated; nam_apap205-7_45 (Oversized 7, Folder 12)
  - Reference Material, 1990-1998; Undated; nam_apap205-7_46 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Reference Material, 1990-1998; Undated; nam_apap205-7_47 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Reference Material, 1990-1998; Undated; nam_apap205-7_48 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Religious Material, 1987; 1990-1999; Undated; nam_apap205-7_49 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Religious Material, 1987; 1990-1999; Undated; nam_apap205-7_50 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Irene Rosenfeld - resume, Undated; nam_apap205-7_51 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Michael Ross - draft articles, Undated; nam_apap205-7_52 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - State of Ohio v. Ediberto Huertas, 1990; nam_apap205-7_53 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The State of Texas v. Robert Wallace West, Jr., 1994; nam_apap205-7_54 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Synopsis of Human Rights Violations and Official Misconduct at Allen County Jail, 1995; nam_apap205-7_55 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Teresa Newsletter #9, 1993; nam_apap205-7_56 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Tim Robbins - interview, 1996; nam_apap205-7_57 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Unknown Articles, Undated; nam_apap205-7_58 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Unknown Conference Call, November 17, 1996; nam_apap205-7_59 (Oversize 9, Cassette 3)
  - Unlabed, Undated; nam_apap205-7_60 (Oversize 9, 5.25in-floppy 2)
  - Unlabed, Undated; nam_apap205-7_61 (Oversize 9, Microcassette 1)
  - William Andrew's Statements, 1992; nam_apap205-7_62 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Works - WS-Abuse, Jan, Undated; nam_apap205-7_63 (Oversize 9, 5.25in-floppy 1)